//@flow

import type {CardType} from "./types.js"

const cardData: CardType[] = [
    {
        front: "le lien",
        back: "link (website)",
    },
    {
        front: "le fureteur",
        back: "(web) browser",
    },
    {
        front: "piger",
        back: "to try your luck (tirer au sort)",
    },
    {
        front: "tirer au sort",
        back: "to draw straws, to try your luck (piger)",
    },
    {
        front: "l'avoine (f)",
        back: "oat(s)",
    },
    {
        front: "les jeux de société",
        back: "games (board, card) played with a group",
    },
    {
        front: "le traineau à chiens",
        back: "dog sledding",
    },
    {
        front: "muet",
        back: "silent",
    },
    {
        front: "épeler",
        back: "to spell",
    },
    {
        front: "la tablette de chocolat",
        back: "chocolate bar (idiom: six-pack abs)",
    },
    {
        front: "ronfler",
        back: "to snore",
    },
    {
        front: "la planche à neige",
        back: "snowboarding",
    },
    {
        front: "accrocher",
        back: "to hook",
    },
    {
        front: "le crochet",
        back: "hook",
    },
    {
        front: "être accro à (q.q.c.)",
        back: "be hooked on something",
    },
    {
        front: "mou",
        back: "soft",
    },
    {
        front: "le chlore",
        back: "chlorine",
    },
    {
        front: "guérir",
        back: "to cure",
    },
    {
        front: "démolir",
        back: "to demolish",
    },
    {
        front: "saler",
        back: "to salt",
    },
    {
        front: "le sol",
        back: "floor",
    },
    {
        front: "s'évanouir",
        back: "faint",
    },
    {
        front: "tomber dans les pommes",
        back: "faint (idiom)",
    },
    {
        front: "un chat dans la gorge",
        back: "frog in the throat (idiom)",
    },
    {
        front: "deviner",
        back: "guess",
    },
    {
        front: "se détendre",
        back: "to relax",
    },
    {
        front: "être à l'aise (avec ...)",
        back: "to be at ease",
    },
    {
        front: "confortable",
        back: "comfortable (only to describe things)",
    },
    {
        front: "se déguiser",
        back: "to disguise (yourself)",
    },
    {
        front: "jouer à cache-cache",
        back: "to play hide and seek",
    },
    {
        front: "le point de suture",
        back: "stitch (medical)",
    },
    {
        front: "une échéance",
        back: "expiration (both as in \"expiration date\" and breathing out)",
    },
    {
        front: "cueillir",
        back: "to pick (fruit, flower, etc.)",
    },
    {
        front: "mûrir",
        back: "to ripen",
    },
    {
        front: "foncé",
        back: "bright (as in color)",
    },
    {
        front: "la virgule",
        back: "comma",
    },
    {
        front: "niaiser",
        back: "say stupid or false things",
    },
    {
        front: "congés payés",
        back: "paid vacation",
    },
    {
        front: "démissioner",
        back: "to resign",
    },
    {
        front: "licencier",
        back: "to fire",
    },
    {
        front: "le stagiaire",
        back: "intern",
    },
    {
        front: "le stage",
        back: "internship",
    },
    {
        front: "coudre",
        back: "to sew",
    },
    {
        front: "peler",
        back: "to peel",
    },
    {
        front: "dépasser",
        back: "go beyond, over (in the sense of a limit)",
    },
    {
        front: "reporter",
        back: "postpone",
    },
    {
        front: "réseau",
        back: "network",
    },
    {
        front: "décrocher",
        back: "pick up (the phone)",
    },
    {
        front: "raccrocher",
        back: "hang up (the phone)",
    },
    {
        front: "l'ébeniste (m)",
        back: "furniture maker (wood), cabinet maker",
    },
    {
        front: "le menuisier",
        back: "carpenter",
    },
    {
        front: "le cadre (sens q.q.u.)",
        back: "executive",
    },
    {
        front: "le chômage",
        back: "unemployment",
    },
];

export default cardData;
